<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name = "heading"> Frequently Asked Questions \n \n </string>
    <string name = "q1">How does this timer work? Is the same timer used on every screen? \n</string>
    <string name = "a1">\n Each activity uses a different timer, however when you change from the scoring screen to
        the video or glossary screen, the time gets carried over to a new timer that is created.
        So as a result the same time will be held in every activity. \n \n</string>

       <string name = "q2"> What if I change from the scoring screen to the glossary screen to the video or scoring screen?\n</string>
        <string name = "a2">\n Even though it is not displayed, if you change to the glossary screen while the timer is
        running in any activity, then a new timer is created that will continue to run behind the scenes,
        so you won\'t see if. That way you can change activities without worrying about there being
        a gap in time. \n \n</string>

       <string name = "q3"> Why is the timer sometimes off by a second between activities? \n</string>
       <string name = "a3"> \n When you change activities, the timer will get carried over to create a new timer in the
        newly accessed activity, which can sometimes result in a second delay when changing activities.
        This will be resolved during the next change in activities. \n \n</string>

        <string name = "q4">Why can I only stop the timer in the video activity, but not resume it? \n</string>

        <string name = "a4">\n This was a design decision  that was intended to help control the
        intended flow of the app. After recording a touch, it was intended that the user would pause
        the timer and navigate to the scoring activity to allocate points, and then restart the timer
        and move back to video mode. In the future this might be changed so that the timer can be
        resumed from the video mode in order to reduce the delay between starting the timer and
        launching the camera. \n \n</string>

        <string name = "q5">Are you affiliated with a particular club or group? \n</string>

        <string name = "a5"> \n Although I am part of a fencing club at Ohio State, this application
        was made independently of any club or organization. The design and name are not intentonally
        derived from any existing club or organization, and any similarities are coincidential and
        are not intended. \n \n</string>

        <string name = "q6">Will there ever be any updates or changes to this app? \n</string>

        <string name = "a6">\n While I cannot say for sure, I will definitely try to update the app in
         the future. However, this depends on how much user feedback I get. I will focus on fixing
        any reported bugs that might arise before I add any new content. If I get a lot of feedback
        that suggests a particular feature, then I will work on implementing it in a future update. \n \n</string>


</resources>